Hey everyone, do you ever feel like your English is kind of stuck on pause?
みんな、英語が一時停止しているように感じたことはある？
You know, when you want to talk about something that's happening right now,
今起こっていることについて話したいとき、
well today we are hitting the play button.
今日はその再生ボタンを押すよ。
We're going to put your English into live action mode
英語を生き生きとした状態にするために、
by mastering something called the present continuous.
「現在進行形」をマスターしよう。
Ready? Let's dive in. So picture this.
準備はいい？さあ、始めよう。
You're watching your favorite gamer streaming live.
お気に入りのゲーマーがライブ配信しているところを想像して。
They're in the middle of an epic boss battle.
彼らは壮大なボス戦の真っ最中。
Do they say, I defeat the boss? No way.
「ボスを倒す」とは言わないよね？
They're yelling, I am defeating the boss. Let's go.
「ボスを倒している」と叫んでいる。
See, that's what we're talking about,
これが私たちが話していることだよ。
that feeling of action happening in real time,
リアルタイムで起こっているアクションの感覚、
and that's exactly what we're gonna learn how to do today.
それを今日は学ぶんだ。
So what's the real difference here? Let's break it down.
では、実際の違いは何だろう？分解してみよう。
On the left, they play baseball on Sundays.
左側は「彼らは日曜日に野球をする」。
That's like a fact in a textbook, right? It's their routine.
これは教科書の事実のようなもの、彼らのルーチン。
But on the right, they are playing baseball now.
でも右側は「彼らは今、野球をしている」。
Boom, suddenly you're right there at the game.
突然、あなたはそのゲームにいる。
You can almost smell the popcorn. It's happening this very second.
ポップコーンの匂いがほとんど感じられる。今、まさに起こっている。
That's the magic of live action English.
これが生き生きとした英語の魔法。
All right, so how do we switch on this live action mode?
さて、この生き生きとした状態にどうやって切り替える？
It's actually super simple. There's a secret formula, just two parts.
実はとても簡単。秘密の公式がある、2つの部分だけ。
And trust me, once you get it, you'll start seeing it everywhere.
信じて、これを理解すれば、どこでも見えるようになる。
Let's check it out. And here it is, the super secret formula.
見てみよう。これが超秘密の公式。
It's like a recipe with just two ingredients.
まるで2つの材料だけのレシピのよう。
First, you need a B verb, that's your am, is, or are.
まず、B動詞が必要、am、is、areのいずれか。
Then you add your main verb with ing, tacked on the end.
次に、主動詞にingを付け加える。
That's the whole thing.
これが全て。
But, and this is super important, you gotta have both.
でも、これがとても重要、両方が必要。
It's like you can't make a sandwich
サンドイッチは
with just one piece of bread, right? It just doesn't work.
1枚のパンだけでは作れないよね？うまくいかない。
Okay, you've got the formula.
さて、公式は分かった。
Now it's time for a little pop quiz, a mini challenge.
次はちょっとしたポップクイズ、ミニチャレンジ。
We're gonna focus on that first ingredient, choosing the right B verb.
最初の材料、正しいB動詞を選ぶことに焦点を当てる。
I'll give you a sentence with a blank space
空白のある文を出すから、
and you try to fill it in in your head. You ready? Let's do this.
頭の中で埋めてみて。準備はいい？やってみよう。
All right, first one up. I blank reading a book now.
最初の文。I blank reading a book now。
What goes in the blank? Hmm, it's am.
空白には何が入る？うーん、amだ。
Of course, I and Am are best friends. They always stick together.
もちろん、Iとamは親友。いつも一緒にいる。
Easy, right? Next. Okay, how about this one?
簡単だよね？次はこれ。
She blank singing a song now. We're talking about one person.
She blank singing a song now。1人のことを話している。
So the B verb is, you got it.
だからB動詞は、そう、isだ。
It's is, she is, he is, my phone is.
She is、He is、My phone is。
If it's one person or thing, you use is, perfect.
1人または1つの物の場合はisを使う、完璧。
And for our last one in this round, we blank doing homework now.
最後の文は、We blank doing homework now。
This time it's a group of people. So it's gotta be R, absolutely.
今回はグループの人々だから、Rだね、絶対に。
We are, they are, my friends are.
We are、They are、My friends are。
Look at that, you've already totally mastered
見て、もうすでに
the first half of our secret formula. Nice work.
秘密の公式の前半を完全にマスターしたよ。素晴らしい。
All right, part one is complete. You've totally nailed the B verbs.
さて、パート1は完了。B動詞は完全に理解した。
Now let's level up to part two, adding that ING at the end.
次はパート2、最後にINGを付け加える。
Most of the time it's super easy,
ほとんどの場合はとても簡単、
but there are a couple of pro-level spelling tricks
でも正しくするためのいくつかのスペルのコツがある。
you need to know to get it right every time.
これを見て、すべてが明確になる。
So check out this table, it makes everything clear.
ルール1、標準のものは簡単。
Rule number one, the standard one is a piece of cake.
ほとんどの動詞、例えばeatは、単にINGを付けるだけ。
For most verbs like eat, you just slap an ING on the end.
はい、eating、すごく簡単。
Bam, eating, so simple.
ルール2は、silent Eで終わる動詞、例えばmake。
Rule two is for verbs that end with that silent E, like make.
Eを取り除いてINGを加えるだけで、makingになる。
But then, then there's rule number three, the special one.
そして、特別なルール3があります。
Look at swim, it becomes swimming with a double M.
swimは、ダブルMでswimmingになります。
So what's up with that? Why does that happen?
これはどういうこと？なぜそうなるの？
Yeah, that's the big question, right?
そう、それが大きな疑問だよね。
That third rule is the one that trips people up.
この3つ目のルールが人を混乱させるんだ。
It feels kind of random. How in the world are you supposed to know
なんだかランダムに感じるよね。どうやって
when to double that last letter? Well, guess what?
最後の文字を重ねるタイミングを知るの？実は、
There's a secret, and it's actually not about spelling.
秘密があって、スペルのことじゃないんだ。
It's about sound. Okay, listen closely because the clue
音に関することなんだ。よく聞いて、ヒントは
is the vowel sound right before that last letter.
最後の文字の前の母音の音だよ。
Let's take the word sit. Hear that IH sound? Sit.
sitという単語を見て。IHの音が聞こえる？sit。
It's short, it's quick, right? Because that vowel is short,
短くて、すばやいよね？その母音が短いから、
you double the T to get sitting. Now compare that to eat.
Tを重ねてsittingになる。次はeatと比べてみて。
Hear that e sound? Eat. It's a long, stretched out sound.
eの音が聞こえる？eat。長く伸びた音だよ。
And for long vowels like that, you just add ing.
長い母音の場合は、ただingを加えるだけ。
No doubling needed, so it becomes eating. Isn't that cool?
重ねる必要はなく、だからeatingになる。面白いよね？
Your ears tell you exactly what to do.
耳が正確に何をすべきか教えてくれる。
Wow, okay, you've got the formula, you've got the spelling rules,
すごい、これで公式もスペルのルールも
you are so close to being a master.
マスターに近づいているよ。
But now it's time for the final expert level secret.
でも、今は最後の専門的な秘密の時間だ。
This is the one thing that even advanced learners sometimes forget.
これは上級者でも時々忘れがちなことだよ。
So let me ask you a question.
では、質問をします。
Can you just take any verb in English and add I-N-G to it?
英語の動詞にI-N-Gを加えることができる？
Just throw it into live action mode? What do you think?
そのままアクションモードにできると思う？
The answer is nope, you can't.
答えは、できない、です。
And understanding why is gonna make your English
その理由を理解することで、英語が
sound so much more natural. Okay, look at this.
もっと自然に聞こえるようになるよ。さて、これを見て。
On the left, he is playing the piano. Yeah, that sounds perfect.
左側は、彼がピアノを弾いている。完璧な音だね。
Playing is an action. You can see it, you can hear it.
playingはアクションだ。目に見えて、聞こえる。
But now look at the right side. He is knowing Helen.
でも右側を見て。彼はヘレンを知っている。
Oof, something about that just sounds weird, doesn't it?
うーん、それはなんだか変な感じがするよね？
Your brain is telling you that's not right.
脳がそれは違うと言っている。
And that's because no isn't an action.
それは、knowはアクションではないから。
It's a state, a condition you're in.
状態、つまりあなたがいる状況なんだ。
So basically, English has two kinds of verbs.
基本的に、英語には2種類の動詞がある。
You've got your action verbs.
アクション動詞があって、
These are the verbs that love to run around
これらは動き回るのが好きな動詞。
and be in live action mode. But then you have state verbs.
そして、状態動詞がある。
And these verbs, well, they just like to chill.
これらの動詞は、リラックスしているのが好き。
They're not about action. They're about a state of being.
アクションではなく、存在の状態について。
Verbs like no, like, have, or love.
no、like、have、loveのような動詞。
You don't really do these things for a short time.
これらは短時間で行うものではない。
It's just how things are. That's why they don't like using ING.
ただそういうものなんだ。だからINGを使わない。
Okay, final test, lightning round.
さて、最後のテスト、ライトニングラウンド。
Let's see if you can pick the right one.
正しいものを選べるか見てみよう。
Number one, she eats or is eating breakfast now.
1つ目、彼女は今朝食を食べる、または食べている。
Eating is an action, right? So it's is eating, good.
eatingはアクションだよね？だからis eatingが正解。
Number two, he knows or is knowing the answer.
2つ目、彼は答えを知っている、または知っているところだ。
No is a state verb, it likes to chill. So we just say knows.
knowは状態動詞だから、knowsと言うだけ。
And the last one, we have or are having two cats.
最後に、私たちは2匹の猫を持っている、または持っているところだ。
This is about having something, possession, which is a state.
これは何かを持つこと、つまり状態について。
So the answer is have. You see the pattern? You've totally got this.
だから、haveが正解。パターンが見えた？完全に理解してるね。
You're a pro. And just like that, you're in control.
あなたはプロだ。そして、これであなたがコントロールできる。
You now have all the secret formulas, the pro tips,
今、すべての秘密の公式、プロのヒントを持っている。
everything you need to use this grammar perfectly.
この文法を完璧に使うために必要なものはすべて。
Let's just do a super quick review of everything you learned today.
では、今日学んだことを簡単に振り返りましょう。
So here's your final mission briefing.
これがあなたの最終ミッションのブリーフィング。
First, you've got the formula B plus verb ING
まず、今起こっていることにはBプラス動詞INGの公式がある。
for anything happening right now.
次に、3つのスペルルールを知っている。
even the tricky one about doubling the letter.
文字を2倍にする難しいやつもね。
And third, you have the ultimate pro tip.
そして、最後に究極のプロのヒント。
Action verbs go live, but state verbs, they just chill.
動作動詞は生き生きしているけど、状態動詞はのんびりしている。
You know, we started this whole thing,
私たちはこの全てを始めたのは、
just try to figure out how to talk about what's happening right now.
今起こっていることについて話す方法を見つけるため。
And now a sentence like, he is reading a book now
だから「彼は今本を読んでいる」という文が
is super easy for you. You can use that with 100% confidence.
あなたにとってとても簡単になった。自信を持って使えるよ。
See, learning English can be pretty fun when you know the secrets.
ほら、秘密を知れば英語学習は楽しい。
So now it's your turn to go live.
さあ、あなたの番だ。
I mean it, right now, stop and look around you. What's happening?
今すぐ、立ち止まって周りを見て。何が起こっている？
Is the clock on the wall ticking? Are you tapping your foot?
壁の時計は動いている？足をタップしている？
Is a car driving past your window?
窓の外を車が通り過ぎている？
Find one thing, just one, that's happening right now
今起こっていることを一つ見つけて、
and describe it in an English sentence.
それを英語の文で説明してみて。
Put your new superpower to the test. You can do it.
新しいスーパーパワーを試してみて。できるよ。
Thanks so much for hanging out with me today.
今日は一緒にいてくれてありがとう。